本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
About the boy who was pursuing Lascall...
ラスコールを追っていた少年の行方ですが
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
I've yet to find any clues to his whereabouts.
依然手がかりは掴めていません
A red-haired woman has been witnessed
at the scene of several homicides,
赤毛の女は　連続殺人の現場で何度か目撃されているが
but she fled each time.
その度に逃げられている
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
Apparently, she has a scanning ability
similar to the Acting Director's.
代行と同じ索敵系能力を使うようだ
Now that you mention it,
そういえば　キースの屋敷でも
she seemed to have known in advance that
you were coming to Keith's home, Matt.
マットさん来るのを察知していたようでした
Could she have sensory threads?
触角糸でしょうか？
That's very likely the case.
But what is she after?
恐らくな
しかし　狙いはなんだ？
She isn't here, either.
ここにもない　どこだ？
Where are you, Parny Pealrmanta?!
パーニィ＝パールマンタ
止まる者　愚かなりし
The one who stops is foolish
はらりひらり指に触れた黒い翼の　一片
A piece of black wing gently touches fingers
诸
神&动漫国
君が一つの　物語なら
If you were a story
まだいくらでも　掛け替えられる
You could still rewrite it all you want
血のインクは乾かない
The ink of blood doesn't dry up
誰も知らない　本との僕ら
No one knows the real us
荒れた世界　枯れるのは
What changes the chaotic world
追い求めたのは　ちっぽけな幸福なんかじゃない
What we pursued isn't
Small happiness
戦え　轟く　音を合図に
Fight with a rumbling heartbeat as a sign
意のまま　進めば
What awaits you is infinite if you
move forward as you wish
行く先　果てない
抗え　のたうち
Fight off no matter how many
times you get defeated
幾度と　汚れと
Engrave your dream onto the scar you bear
膝を纏った傷跡に夢を
埋もれそうな今日の記憶繋げるために　明日へ
In order to connect today's memory that's
on the verge of being buried to tomorrow
Episode 15
A Girl, a Girl, and the Bed of God
第15话 少女
与
少女
和
神之栖所
I've come for you.
君を迎えに来た
For me?
迎えに？
Because it would be a shame to
lose such an excellent talent.
優秀な人材を失うのは惜しいからね
I'm a traitor.
あたしは裏切り者だ
Oh? Would you tell
me what you did?
さて　君は何をしたのかな？
I lied to Winkeny, tried to get
him to steal Hiza's book,
ウィンケニーを騙し
ハイザの「本」を奪わせようとした
and killed some Mock Men.
「擬人」たちも殺してる
Ah, that's nothing.
ささいなことだ
I'm after Lascall Othello.
ラスコール＝オセロを追っている
You're fighting a battle you cannot win.
君は勝ち目のない戦いを挑んでいる
And for a man who rejected you, no less.
それも自分を捨てた男のために
黙れ！
Shut up!
Damn!
くそ
お前…
You...
What is it? I'll face you if I have to.
どうした？　相手になるよ
You were playing the violin the
other night, as well, right?
あなただったのね　この間の夜のヴァイオリンも
The other night? And what if I was?
この間？
だったらどうした？
It sounds dreadful.
いやな音ね
それは失礼　お嬢ちゃんのお気に召さなかったようで
Well, I'm sorry it's not up to
your refined taste, missy.
Though it sounds dreadful, for some reason,
it pierced me to the heart.
いやな音だけど
なぜか胸に刺さった
What the? Weirdo!
なんだ　お前
変なやつだ
You're fighting while trying to
uncover the correct answer.
お前は正解を探しながら戦っている
Is killing the answer?
Is not killing the answer?
殺すのが正解か　殺さないのが正解か
What's your point?
だからどうしたっていうの
I'm saying you're weak.
だから弱い
I kill because I want to,
あたしは殺したいから殺す
regardless of whether it's right or not.
正解であろうとなかろうと関係ない
And that's something you can't do.
あんたにはそれができない
Of course not! I'm an Armed Librarian!
武装司書として当然のことよ
私たちは秩序のために戦っている
We fight for peace!
And therein lies the problem, missy.
You can't win like that.
駄目だよ　お嬢ちゃん　それじゃ勝てない
Wait! Answer my question!
待ちなさい！
答えて！あなたたち神溺教団とラスコール＝オセロは関係あるの
Are you Church members connected
to Lascall Othello somehow?
Under no circumstance is
Lascall Othello to be pursued.
ラスコール＝オセロを追ってはならない
Those who do will face certain death.
追う者には死　あるのみ
え？
What?
ふっ　笑わせる
You're funny.
お嬢ちゃんの手に負える相手じゃないよ
Lascall Othello is out of your league.
あいつを殺すのは　このあたしさ
I will be the one to kill him!
Then Lascall actually...
じゃ　ラスコールは…
Wait a second, Milepoc!
落ち着け　ミレポ
Lascall Othello really exists!
ラスコール＝オセロは実在するんです
A member of the Church
acknowledged his existence.
神溺教団の者も存在を認めています
伝説は本当だったんです
The legend is true...
Milepoc!
ミレポ
We'll discuss this later. Understood?
後で話そう　いいな
はい
Okay.
Found it!
あった
True happiness rests within you.
君の心には確たる幸福の形がある
You have what it takes
to become a True Man.
君には「真人」となる資格がある
I want to act...
私は　演じたいの
I want to act forever!
いつまでも永遠に　演じ続けたい
A pure desire to act...
A desire stronger than any others'.
誰にも負けない演じることへの純粋な欲望を
We shall prepare a stage for you.
我々が舞台を用意いたしましょう
We shall silence all critics.
批判する者は黙らせましょう
君はただ演ずればいい　君の思うままに
You are to act. That's all.
Act as your heart desires.
Ah, this is pure bliss.
ああ　あたしは幸福よ
I'd walk through fire if it
would allow me to act.
演じるためなら　どんな苦労も厭わない
世界中が　あたしの演技を待っていてくれるから
The entire world is awaiting my performances!
見事な演技でした
That was a beautiful performance.
You've scored another blockbuster.
今度のシネマも大当たりでございます
Blockbuster?!
何か大当たりよ　私に才能なんてない
I'm a talentless hack.
The more I try to act,
the more apparent it becomes.
演じれば演じるほど分かるの
パーニィ＝パールマンタは　あんたたちが作った幻
Parny Pealrmanta is just an
illusion you people created.
Tell me, how much longer?
ねえ　まだなの？
Lascall will come once I attain
happiness, won't he?
幸せになれば　ラスコールが来てくれるんでしょう？
He'll take my book to Heaven, won't he?
あたしの「本」を天国に運んでくれるんでしょう？
ねえ　探して　ラスコールに早く会わせて
Please look for him!
Hurry and let me meet Lascall!
The stone sword of spent time, Yor...
過ぎ去りし石剣――「夜」よ
We should have harvested you earlier,
もっと早く摘み取って置くべきだった
at the peak of your happiness.
幸せの絶頂にいた頃に
幸福を見失った「真人」に　もはや価値はございません
A True Man who has lost sight
of happiness is worthless.
Letting you meet Lascall Othello
is our final act of mercy.
ラスコール＝オセロに会わせてやったのは
我々から君への最後の慈悲だ
Then what was that?
What is a True Man anyway?!
なんなのよ？
「真人」って　一体なんなのよ？
No different from livestock, really.
あえて言うなら　家畜かな
Livestock that gives birth
to happiness, for God.
神のために幸福を生む家畜だ
Then... What is God?
じゃあ　神って　何？
Huh? So that's what happened to her.
なんだ　そういうことか
I had to go all over the place,
but in the process, I figured it out...
遠回りしたけど　おかげで分かったよ
When a man from the Church of
Drowning in God's Grace dies,
神溺教団のものが死ねば　その「本」を回収し
Lascall Othello appears
to collect his book.
ラスコール＝オセロは現われる
Excuse me.
あのう　武装司書の方ですよね
You're an Armed Librarian, aren't you?
僕を探してるって聞いたんですけど
I heard you've been looking for me...
Huh?
え？
My name is Luliy Strite.
ルリィ＝ストライトと言います
Why are you looking
for Lascall Othello?
どうしてラスコールのことを？
父のシャール＝ストライトは行商人でした
My father, Challe Strite,
was a traveling street peddler.
He was rarely home,
あまり家にいなくて
but every once in a while,
he'd come back with huge sums of money.
時々使い切れないぐらいの大金を持って帰って来て
Then one day, we lost contact with him.
それが突然　連絡もつかなくなったんです
I searched for him.
僕は父を探しました
そして　ある町で会えたんです
Then, one day, I found him
in a town someplace.
But...
でも…
But?
でも？
父は自分のことは忘れろと言いました
He told me to forget about him.
その時　一緒にいた人たちからこう呼ばれていたんです
And the people there called him...
Lascall Othello.
ラスコール＝オセロと
What's the matter?
どうしたんですか？
Oh, I'm sorry. It's nothing.
御免なさい　なんでもないの
I see... So that's all it is.
そう　そういうことだったの
I'm so stupid.
馬鹿みたい
He's just a man who adopted
the name from the legend.
敵は伝説の名を騙っていただけ
I have nothing to fear.
恐れることなどない
Where are you going?
どこ行くんですか？
To my hotel, just for a bit.
一先ず　私のホテルに
Are you going to fight my father?
父と戦うんですか？
I don't know.
それは分からないわ
Father?
父さん？
What is it?
どうしたの？
I just saw my father!
今父さんが…
Huh?
え？
Don't!
いけない　ルリィ
Luliy!
Father!
父さん
My son.
息子よ
Don't go to him! Luliy!
駄目　ルリィ
You should have picked
どちらか一方になさるのが　ようございましたな
one or the other.
Fath...
とう…さん…
私を殺すか　ルリィを助けるか
Are you going to kill me?
Are you going to save Luliy?
どうして？　どうして殺した？
Why... Why did you kill him?
Killing at point-blank range is
the most efficient method.
簡単な所から仕留めるのが効率ようございます
First, Luliy.
まずはルリィ　次にアルメ
Next will be Alme.
Lastly, you and Mattalast.
最後に　あなたとマットアラスト
You're still in here, huh?
まだここにいたのか
If what you say is true,
君の報告どおりだとすると
敵はどこにでも現れる
the enemy can appear anywhere, anytime.
It's dangerous to be alone.
一人になるのが危険だ
Matt, do you remember
マットさん　覚えていますか
私と始めて会った時のことを
the day we met?
ああ　グインベクスの反乱終結の時だったな
Yeah. The Guinbecs revolt
had just been quelled.
グインベクス軍は壊滅
The Guinbecs army was wiped out.
But the students in the military
academy continued classes.
だが　士官学校の生徒たちは講義を続けていた
You prevented any faculty or students
who tried to escape from doing so.
逃げ出そうとした教官や生徒たちを　君が引き止めたそうだな
士官候補生が講義時間に講義を受けることは正しい行動だと
You said, "When class is in session, the proper
thing for an officer in training to do
is to be in class."
講堂内は禁煙です
No smoking in the lecture hall!
結局　私は規則に従っているだけなんです
All I've been doing is blindly
following the rules.
いつも自分で判断しようとしてない
I never tried judging the
situation for myself.
You were right, Alme...
本当　あなたの言う通りね　アルメ
I'm weak, aren't I?
私は　弱いですね
You finally figured it out.
やっと分かったか
Huh?
え？
Well? Will you just end things as
they stand, Milepoc Finedel?
それで　お前はそこで終わりなのか？
ミレポック＝ファインデル
Cigal was a foolish man.
シガルは愚かな男でした
He never loved you.
あなたを愛してもいなかった
How do you know that?
なんでお前に分かる？
I've read his Book.
あの方の「本」を読んでございます？
Do you think you can win against me?
勝てると思いですか
I found you!
見つけたわ
お前
You...
よくも騙したわね
You lied to me.
何がだ？
About what?
ラスコールよ
About Lascall!
あなたも彼の秘密を隠すために動いていたんでしょう
Everything you did was a big
ruse to protect his secret.
What are you talking about?
何を言っている
I'm fighting Lascall right now!
あたしは今ラスコールと戦ってんだ
I see right through your lies!
見え透いた嘘
How?
なぜ？
Did you forget about my ability?
私の能力を忘れた？
Tele... pathy...
「思考…共有」
You never expected us to team
up against you, huh?
まさか　あたしたちが手を組むとは思わなかったろう
If Alme and I were to fight,
私とアルメが戦ったら
あなたはどちらかが倒れた時に必ず現れる
the moment one of us was
defeated, you'd appear.
そのほうが効率がいいでしょうからね
That was the most efficient method, right?
I'm genuinely impressed...
お見事で…ございます
How do you feel, having killed a man?
人を殺した感想は？
後悔ばかりよ
Full of regret.
あなたは？
How about you?
あなたもラスコールを追っていたのでしょう？
You were pursuing Lascall,
too, weren't you?
別に　あたしは何も変わらないさ
Actually, I don't feel any different at all.
You can chase the past...
過去を追い掛けても
You can chase things you've lost...
なくしたものを追いかけても　何も生まれない
But nothing will come from it.
That's how I felt when I heard
you playing the violin.
あなたのヴァイオリンを聞いた時　そんな気がした
You're the second person, Milepoc...
あんたが二人目だったよ　ミレポック
あたしのヴァイオリンを気に入ってくれたのは
The second person to like my music.
Shall we get started, Alme?
そろそろ始めましょうか　アルメ
Nothing will come from the past.
過去　何も生まれない
That means I can't win.
ならあたしは勝てない
She changed,
こいつは変わった
but I...
でも　あたしは…
Alme, now I know...
アルメ　よく分かったわ
I'm weak.
私は弱いのね
No matter where I go,
I cannot fight alone.
どこまで行っても　私は一人では戦えない
Even against Lascall,
I needed you as an ally.
ラスコールを倒す時ですら
あなたという仲間が必要だった
You are strong.
あなたは強い
たった一人で戦おうとした
You tried to fight him alone.
I respect your willpower.
その意志の力は尊敬するわ
However, I'm going to win.
でもね　勝つのは私の
Because...
なぜなら…
... you're all alone.
あなたは一人だから
You use sensory threads, don't you?
触角糸を使うんでしょう
I spoke over telepathy to avoid tipping you off.
注意を逸らすために　「思考共有」で話しかけていたのよ
That's how I fight.
これが　私の戦い方
That's fine.
それでいいさ
Fine...
それで…
You did well. Let's get out of here.
よくやった　ミレポ
Okay.
はい
Ah, this is...
あ　これは…
I'm so happy, Master Cigal.
シガル様　アルメは幸福です
I'm but a lowly Mock Man, serving a True Man.
「真人」にお使いする「擬人」の分際で
こんなに幸せでよいのでしょうか
Is it right for me to feel this happy?
Get out of here, you damned pig!
出て行け　この豚め
あ　なぜ分からない
Ah, why doesn't she understand?!
That pig... That damned pig!
豚め　豚どもめ
世界中で幸福になるのは
The only one in the world to find happiness
美しく立派な「本」となるのは この私だけなのだ
and have a glorious, beautiful Book will be me!
こんなことのために
All for that reason...
You young girls with radiant gem-like
glows hidden in your hearts...
宝石のような輝きを　その胸に秘めた少女たち
あなた方も　真実に辿り着くことは叶いませんでした
Like the others,
you never reached the truth.
However, I must salute your foolish,
unmitigated devotion.
しかし　その愚かなまでに
一途な想いに私は　敬意を表します
All the eye sees is a lie.
目に映るものはすべて偽り
この神の石剣こそ　我が実態
This stone sword of the gods, itself, is I...
The stone sword of spent time, Yor.
過ぎ去りし石剣――「夜」よ
I possess the ability to alter
a person's perception.
私は人の認識を操作する能力を持っている
Like I did with Luliy.
このルリィも　また然り
I suppose you're more than
meets the eye, too, huh?
貴様も　そこにいるとは限らないわけか
すべては幻だ
It's all an illusion.
幻ね
An illusion, huh?
I was surprised when you
all contacted me.
君達から連絡がきたときは　驚いたよ
だが　うまくいった
Nevertheless, everything went well.
We minimized damage
by slaying the traitor,
我々は被害を最小限に裏切り者を葬り
and you were able to save the
young Armed Librarian's life.
君達は若き武装司書の命を守ることができた
Those who pursue Lascall
meet certain death.
ラスコールを追う者には死　あるのみ
That is true,
それは真実だ　我々が殺すのだからな
because we kill them.
There is one objective toward which
神溺教団と武装司書は
ある一点において常に協力関係にある
the Church and the Armed
Librarians help each other.
Then... What is God?
じゃあ　神って　何？
I refer to protecting the secret
behind Lascall Othello and Heaven.
ラスコール＝オセロを
そして天国の秘密を守るという点においては
I wonder how Heaven's doing.
天国の様子はいかがかな？
Lascall Othello is a mysterious,
mysterious proprietor of books.
ラスコール＝オセロは不思議な不思議な本屋さんです
不思議な力で「本」を集め
With his mysterious power,
he gathers books and flies around the globe.
不思議な力で世界を飛び回ります
Then, when girls die, having never told
the person they love their feelings,
そして　恋する少女が思いを伝えられず命を落としたとき
he delivers their book to their beloved.
その「本」を思い人へと届けてあげるのです
お終い
The End.
Lost the light
Before closing the sun
If it's a sparkling storm
Jump in before it tempts
The end comes to everyone one day
When the day comes
Aim for the future that begins to move
Even if it's already been written
Search and even acquire the
meaning of getting hurt
In order to be myself
A Banned Book,
There is something that even
the Sacred Eyes cannot see:
聖浄眼でも見えぬものがある
A Banned Book, a Coward,
There is something that even
the Sacred Eyes cannot see:
A Banned Book, a Coward,
one's own dominant trait,
それは己の相
the sight of one's face gazing back
at a past they've long abandoned.
捨てたはずの過去を眺める
A Banned Book, a Coward, and the Sacred Eyes
the sight of one's face gazing back
at a past they've long abandoned.
禁书与废物和圣洁眼
the sight of one's face gazing back
at a past they've long abandoned.
己の横顔